Guide to the Ralph Stockman Tarr papers, 1883-1961,
Tarr, Ralph Stockman papers
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Ralph Stockman Tarr papers, 1883-1961, 1883-1912 (bulk)
14-15-92
(Ralph Stockman), Tarr 1864-1912.
6.2 cubic ft.
Correspondence, field notebooks, research material, publications
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Tarr's papers mainly pertaining to geography.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Professor of geology.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Papers include irrigation surveys of western states, 1883-1889; pictures of the Peary Arctic Expedition of 1896; diary of the expedition by B. Hoppin; scrapbook kept by Tarr as a Cornell professor; geology field books; notebooks of his son, Russel S. Tarr; diary kept on the Cornell Alaska Expedition, 1906; lectures on the geography of North America; notes on lab work in an experimental physiography course, 1907-1908; glass slides and negatives; and correspondence on Tarr's early years. Also, Geology Department records and reports kept by Tarr and his successors and a ledger of information on graduate students in the Geology Department.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Tarr, Ralph S.1864-1912.; Tarr, Russel S.; Cornell University--Faculty.; Cornell University--Students.; Cornell University.Dept. of Geology.; Peary Arctic Expedition, 1896.; Cornell Alaska Expedition, 1906.
Subjects:
Geology--Study and teaching.; Geologists.
Form and Genre Terms:
Negatives.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- U.S. Coast and Geodetic Survey maps; publication on the Greenland expedition; Alaska-Yukon Magazine, April, 1909; Scrapbook of memorabilia from various geological society meetings; much loose material, includes TLS from Theodore Roosevelt, 1909 (Box 1)
- Photographs and postcards from Greenland; published diary of Peary Arctic Expedition of 1896; Volume - Dept. records and correspondence, 1892-1894; reports and correspondence, 1895-1914 (Tarr and von Engeln); reports and correspondence, 1910-1962 (Tarr and von Engeln), 1892-1962 (Box 2)
- Maps of Switzerland, field notebooks/diaries, n.d. (Box 3)
- Field notebooks/diaries, n.d. (Box 4)
- Field notebooks/diaries, n.d. (Box 5)
- Notes on the Work in the Laboratory of Experimental Physiography, Year 1907-1908; Geography Course Transcript; Geography Course Syllabus; Flag from 1896 Greenland expedition; Modification of topography by Glacial Erosion; Alaska Diary; 2 glass negatives - campus scenes, 1907-1908 (Box 6)
- Glass negatives of ice experiments at Cornell, 1911-1912 (Box 16)
- Greenland expedition and misc. (4x5 film negatives), 1896 (Box 16)
  Includes tve_exp1896_001-291
- Greenland expedition and misc. (mostly 5x7 film negatives), 1896 (Box 8)
  Includes tve_exp1896_292-318
- Greenland/Alaska negatives, 1906 (Box 16)
  Includes tve_exp1906_001-074
- Greenland/Alaska glass slides, 1906 (Box 17)
  Includes tve_exp1906_075-240
- Alaska expeditions (5x7 and 8x10 glass negatives, 1895-1909 (Box 12)
- Alaskan expeditions: Yakutat Peninsula (prints), 1906-1909 (Box 14)
- Key to slides and classification: Geology Department records, n.d. (Box 10)
- Alaskan Expedition: Tarr and von Engeln (glass and film negatives), 1909 (Box 11, 12)
  Includes tve_exp1909_001-049
- Alaskan Expedition: Tarr and von Engeln (film negatives), 1909 (Box 7)
  Includes tve_exp1909_050-383
- Alaskan Expedition: Tarr and von Engeln (glass negatives), 1909 (Box 8-9)
  Includes tve_384-542, with some gaps
- Alaskan Expedition: Tarr and von Engeln (film negatives), 1911 (Box 13)
  Includes tve_exp1911_001-354
- Ithaca and campus (glass and film negatives), 19-- (Box 9)
  Includes tve_ithaca_026-044, 056-054
- Ice movement observations (glass negatives); images from Ithaca area (photographs, and film and glass negatives), 19-- (Box 14)
  Includes tve_ithaca_003-025, _045
- Alaska and North America, 1905 (Box 15)
  Includes tve_exp1905_001-182
- Glass lantern slides of glaciers, scenes from Japan, and Eskimo women. (Box 21)
- Original sleeves from glass slides, including from Ithaca (undated), 1905, 1906, 1909, 1911 (Box 22)
- Glass lantern slides of glaciers, Alaska and Greenland, slides 1-60 (Box 18)
- Glass lantern slides of glaciers, Alaska and Greenland, slides 61-120 (Box 19)
- Glass lantern slides of glaciers, Alaska and Greenland, slides 121-180 (Box 20)
- Glass lantern slides of glaciers, Alaska and Greenland, slides 181-240 (Box 23)
- Glass lantern slides of glaciers, Alaska and Greenland, slides 241-308 (Box 24)